Ghada ElBadawy

Lecturer

- (1A) Road 200- Degla Maadi Cairo, Egypt
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ghadaahmed-09282816a

- 01068831681
- fafaghouki@gmail.com

Experienced, Passionate and dedicated lecturer with 15 years of experience developing and implementing diverse curriculums covering wide range of subjects. Highly skilled at motivating students through positive encouragement and reinforcement of concepts via interactive classroom instruction and observation. Equipped with extensive background in versatile education environments. Student-centric instructor, academic facilitator and motivational coach. Competent at performing independently or as member of teaching team. Well-versed in classroom and online technologies. Committed to enhancing overall student success by maintaining productive relationships with students and parents. Knowledgeable instructor with strong understanding of teaching:

- · Modern Management
- ·The Essentials of Entrepreneurship and Small Business
- ·Strategic Management
- · Human Resources Management
- · Managerial Policies and Organization Development
- · Public Administration
- · Knowledge Management
- · Organizational Behavior
- · International Business
- · Business Administration



Skills

- Entrepreneurship expertise
- Managerial skills
- Effective managerial techniques
- Lesson Planning
- Curriculum Development
- Classroom technology
- Experiential learning
- Classroom management

- Team building
- Communications
- Problem resolution
- Group and individual instruction
- Student engagement
- Learner assessment



Work History

2020-02 - Current

Entrepreneurship E-Club Manager

Egyptian Chinese University (ECU), Cairo, Egypt

- Organizing two students entrepreneurship competitions annually: Ideation Camp.
- Organizing an entrepreneurship week at the university.
- The presence of representatives of the Entrepreneurship Club in all colleges.
- Helping the most Qualifying teams to apply to a technology incubator.
- Inviting a distinguished public figure in the field of startups and entrepreneurship to give lectures at the university.
- Establish a training camp for Design Thinking training.
- Enhancing the entrepreneurial capabilities of students to find entrepreneurial ideas for future projects.
- Building a culture of entrepreneurship and developing the capabilities of entrepreneurs to enable them to successfully establish and manage small enterprises.
- Creating a generation of entrepreneurs capable of finding investment opportunities for themselves and others.
- Providing semi-industrial prototypes that help the smooth transition of ideas from basic research into developing and marketing products.
- Promote and spread the culture of innovation among all ECU students.
- Motivating the inventors and innovators and investing in their innovations and talents with the purpose of converting them to economic products.

Project Coordinator - Finnish HEI- ICI Program

Egyptian Chinese University (ECU), Cairo, Egypt

- Transitioned projects from estimation and pre-construction phase to well-defined project execution plan.
- Planned and arranged meetings with external organizations and individuals, enabling all parties to meet and discuss project progress.
- Built strong relationships with internal and external stakeholders and devised strategies, initiatives, and events promoting products and services.

Lecturer of Business Administration

Egyptian Chinese University (ECU), Cairo, Egypt

- Prepared course materials such as syllabus, assignments, activities and handouts.
- Evaluated and graded class attendance, assignments, and papers.
- Prepared quizzes, tests and examinations to gauge how well students were

2019-07 - Current

2019-02 - Current

learning.

- Instructed up to 600 students individually and in groups on Modern Management and Organizational Behavior subjects.
- Instructed up to 300 students individually and in groups on Entrepreneurship and Small Business Course.
- Scheduled 6 hours per week to provide academic support and tutoring to struggling students.
- Assisted students of all ability levels develop life-long learning skills and good study habits.
- Worked with staff members to design comprehensive and individualized plans to optimize student education.
- Shifted between formal and informal methods of teaching to keep students interested, including debates, practical activities and experiments.
- Communicated frequently with parents, students and faculty to provide feedback and discuss instructional strategies.
- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional approaches and innovative classroom activities.
- Kept students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Created and developed lesson plans according to students' academic needs, including both group and individual work.
- Participated in department meetings to provide input to colleagues about student achievement and improvement.
- Fostered student curiosity and interest through creative hands-on activities.
- Observed and evaluated students' performance, behavior, social development.

Part Time Lecturer of Business Administration

AAST. (English And French Section), Cairo, Egypt

Lecturer of Business Administration

Modern Academy For Computer Sciences & Management, Cairo, Egypt

- Prepared course materials such as syllabus, assignments, activities and handouts.
- Evaluated and graded class attendance, assignments, and papers.
- Prepared quizzes, tests and examinations to gauge how well students were learning.
- Instructed up to 650 students on Principles of Management & Organization.
- Scheduled 6 hours per week to provide academic support and tutoring to struggling students.
- Assisted students of all ability levels develop life-long learning skills and good study habits.
- Worked with staff members to design comprehensive and individualized plans to optimize student education.
- Shifted between formal and informal methods of teaching to keep students interested, including debates, practical activities and experiments.
- Communicated frequently with parents, students and faculty to provide feedback and discuss instructional strategies.
- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional

2019-02 - Current

2016-10 - 2018-12

approaches and innovative classroom activities.

- Kept students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Created and developed lesson plans according to students' academic needs, including both group and individual work.
- Participated in department meetings to provide input to colleagues about student achievement and improvement.
- Fostered student curiosity and interest through creative hands-on activities.
- Observed and evaluated students' performance, behavior, social development.

Assistant Lecturer

Modern Academy For Computer Sciences & Management, Cairo, Egypt

- Initiated and facilitated classroom discussions.
- Reviewed teaching activities and identified and implemented strategies to improve student learning outcomes.
- Participated in weekly faculty meetings and contributed to curriculum review.
- Developed easy and open rapport with students to encourage engagement and academic progress.
- Supported positive image of university by being responsive and promptly responding to requests and inquiries.
- Met with students during and after office hours to address concerns and offer feedback, and resolve students' behavioral and academic issues.
- Shifted between formal and informal methods of teaching to keep students interested, including debates, practical activities and experiments.

Teaching Assistant

Modern Academy For Computer Sciences & Management, Cairo, Egypt

Education

Political Science

Faculty Of Economics And Political Sciences - Cairo University

B.Sc. Degree: Major in political Science (French Section), Minor in Computational Socio.

Graduation Project: The problem of South Sudan: "The Role of U.S.A in the Mashakus Treaty."

M.D.: Public Administration

AAST. - Cairo

Ph.D.: Public Administration

Sadat Academy For Management Sciences (SAMS) - Cairo



Languages

Arabic

French

English





2007-09 - 2016-09

2005-09 - 2007-09

2000-09 - 2004-05

2005-04 - 2007-09

2010-09 - 2016-10



Certifications

2020-02

2019-09

2019-10

2019-11

2001-10

1999-04

2010-09

2011-12

- International Certified in Entrepreneurship Faculty Development Program in Entrepreneurship Education – Wadwhani Foundation
- Strategy and National Security Nasser Military Academy
- Crisis Management Nasser Military Academy
- Decision Making- Nasser Military Academy
- DELF First Degree (A1, A2, A3, A4), the French Embassy in Cairo, (French Center for culture and Cooperation)
- Alliance French Language Diploma
- TOEFI, Sadat Academy for Management Sciences (SAMS)
- ICDL Certificate



Interests

- Volunteer Work/Community Involvement.
- Reading
- Travelling
- Attending Scientific Conferences



Additional Information

PREVIOUS TRAINING

Employer: Al- Ahram Strategic Center

Job Title: Political Researcher From: July 2003 To: August 2003 Employer: CEDEJ, Cairo, Egypt. Job Title: Political Researcher From: July 2002 To: August 2002

Employer: Radio and Television Union (Radio News Section), Cairo, Egypt.

Job Title: News Translator (From Arabic to French)

From: July 2001 To: August 2001

FORUMS:

- The World Youth Forum in Sharm ElSheik 2018
- Egypt Economic Forum: Smart Vision 10th annual summit March 2018.
- The World Youth Forum in Sharm ElSheik 2019